Part man, part machine, all cop.
RoboCop is a action, thriller, science fiction film directed by Paul Verhoeven.
In a violent, near-apocalyptic Detroit, evil corporation Omni Consumer Products wins
a contract from the city government to privatize the police force.
To test their crime-eradicating cyborgs, the company leads street cop Alex Murphy into an armed confrontation
with crime lord Boddicker so they can use his body to support their untested RoboCop prototype.
But when RoboCop learns of the company's nefarious
plans, he turns on his masters.
Officer Alex J. Murphy / RoboCop, played by Peter Weller.
Officer Anne Lewis, played by Nancy Allen.
The Old Man, played by Dan O'Herlihy.
Dick Jones, played by Ronny Cox.
Clarence Boddicker, played by Kurtwood Smith.
Bob Morton, played by Miguel Ferrer.
RoboCop is a 1987 American science fiction action film directed by Paul
Verhoeven and written by Edward Neumeier and Michael Miner.
The film stars Peter Weller, Nancy Allen, Daniel O'Herlihy,
Ronny Cox, Kurtwood Smith, and Miguel Ferrer.
Set in a crime-ridden Detroit in the near future, RoboCop centers on police officer Alex Murphy (Weller) who is murdered by a
gang of criminals and revived by the megacorporation Omni Consumer Products as the cyborg law enforcer RoboCop.
Unaware of his former life, RoboCop executes a campaign against crime while
coming to terms with the lingering fragments of his humanity.
The film was conceived by Neumeier while working on the set of Blade
Runner (1982), and he developed the idea with Miner.
Their script was purchased in early 1985 by producer
Jon Davison on behalf of Orion Pictures.
Finding a director proved difficult; Verhoeven dismissed the script twice because he did not
understand its satirical content, until he was convinced of its value by his wife.
Filming took place between August and October 1986, mainly in Dallas,
Texas with additional filming in Las Colinas and Pittsburgh.
Rob Bottin led the special-effects team in creating practical
effects, violent gore and the RoboCop costume.
Verhoeven emphasized violence throughout the film, making
it so outlandish that it became comical.
Censorship boards believed that it was too extreme and several scenes were
shortened or modified to receive an acceptable theatrical rating.
RoboCop was a financial success upon its release in
July 1987, earning $53.4 million.
Reviewers praised it as a clever action film with deeper philosophical
messages and satire, but were conflicted about its extreme violence.
The film was nominated for several awards, and won an
Academy Award and a number of Saturn Awards.
RoboCop has been critically reevaluated since its release, and it has been hailed as one of the best
films of the 1980s and one of the greatest science fiction and action films ever made.
The film has been praised for its depiction of a robot affected by the loss of humanity,
in contrast to the stoic and emotionless robotic characters of that era.
RoboCop has continued to be analyzed for its themes such as the nature of humanity, personal identity,
corporate greed and corruption, and is seen as a rebuke of the era's Reaganomics policies.
Its success created a franchise: the sequels RoboCop 2 (1990) and RoboCop 3 (1993), children's animated series,
live-action television shows, video games, comic books, toys, clothing and other merchandise.
A remake was released in 2014.
The film explores themes of experiment, cyborg,
crime fighter, dystopia, giant robot.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.